英國人擁有超過兩千萬個紋身
With over 20 million tattoos,
這讓它成為歐洲紋身數量最多的國家
Britain is the most tattooed nation in Europe.
安全
Safety.
我要趁著酒勁紋一個
I'm definitely got to get a drunken tattoo.
我屁股上一邊有一個  腳趾上還有一個
I've got one on both arse cheeks, one on my toe.
她正在紋活在夢中
She is living the dream!
活在夢中
[拉丁語]
我真的活在夢里啦
I am living the dream!
現在紋身就像一種時尚飾品
It's like a fashion accessory now.
以前只有流氓飛車黨光頭仔和軍人才會來紋身
Before you had to be a thug, biker, skinhead, services,
現在已經成為一種時尚
it's fashionable now.
我剛紋了自己的第一個紋身誒
Ah, I just got my first tattoo!
隨著大街上的紋身工作室越來越多
With more tattoo studios on our high streets than ever before,
讓更多的人嘗試了紋身
more inches of our skin are getting covered in ink.
試過第一次的人中只有1%不會再次紋身
Once you've had one, there's only about 1% never come back.
有些紋身很不錯
Some of it good...
你會不會激動到哭
Are you going to cry?
會啊
Yeah!
有些就不那么友好了
Some of it, not so good.
如果你是白人盎格魯-撒克遜新教徒
If you're White Anglo-Saxon Protestant,
WASP原義是指美國的新教上流社會
即殖民時期來自英國的移民
這就真是種族歧視了
it is really racist.
當你能在幾分鐘內就能被打上終身烙印
But when you can be branded for life in just a few minutes...
我有點醉了  希望紋身別太糟糕
Well, I'm a little bit drunk, so hopefully it won't be too bad.
總會有人后悔的
There will be tattoo regrets.
這個紋身對我來說更像是傷疤
It's become more of a scar than a tattoo.
有人出于愛情
Over love...
我就是放不下
And I just can't move on.
有人已然上癮
Addiction.
我愛紋身  一紋就停不下來了
I love tattoos. Once you pop, you can't stop.
也有些只是酒后興起
Drunken mistakes.
馬丁
是個
傻逼
我把他名字紋在屁股上了
His name on my arse.
還有迷戀別人的
And obsession.
當你愛上某個人
If there's love,
就會想讓全世界都知道
you want the whole world to know.
不會去隱藏
You're not going to hide it.
我的紋身情結
■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：yanghai0810    Gabrielle   瀟湘月影   baby無恥
嗨  老板
Hi, boss.
你好  老兄
Hi, mate.
翻譯：男人不讓紋身的忻      無敵小熊     麥克杜杜格
我胸口有個紋身
Got this tattoo on my chest,
你能不能幫我把它蓋住
but I want to know, can you cover it up?
校對：早先森    時間軸：numbercoco
好的  先看看吧
Oh, right, let's have a look.
把外套脫了
Just take your jacket off.
后期&特效：蠟筆小新的眉毛    總監： zhanginfo
戴夫·弗利特在威爾士的布萊克伍德
Dave Fleet owns Abracadabra Tattoo Studios
開了家魔咒紋身工作室
in Blackwood, Wales,
而且他是覆蓋紋身的專家
and is the go-to artist for cover-up tattoos.
吉尼斯世界紀錄證書
戴夫·弗利特于2011年10月27日至29日
在英國加的夫灣的格羅夫納賭場
為詹姆斯·盧埃林紋身持續50小時10分鐘
獲世界最長紋身時間紀錄
我在魔咒紋身室干了34年了
Abracadabra has been my life now for 34 years.
我們大部分的工作
Biggest part of our work
就是去掩蓋那些...
is covering up a lot of tattoos which are not...
不太理想的紋身
not very good at all.
這棟樓里有四間工作室
There's four studios in this building
都是做覆蓋紋身的
and we're all doing cover-up work.
但戴夫還從沒見過這樣的
But Dave's never seen anything quite like this.
[夢幻船宴網]
fantasyboatparty.com
世界最好的船宴
你怎么會紋個這種東西
How on earth do you have that done?
2005年的時候我去了趟阿伊納帕
Well, I went out to Ayia Napa in 2005
結果兩周的假期變成了三年
and that two week holiday turned into a three year holiday
這就是我上班的地方
and that's where I worked.
老天
Oh, my God!
那時候挺爽的
It was good at the time!
看起來好像一部爛電影
It looks like a mucky film!
這要怎么搞啊
What are we going to do with that?
27歲的馬特·比芬在阿伊納帕工作了三年
27 year-old Matt Buffin spent three years working in Ayia Napa.
但這不是他唯一一個酒后紋身
But it's not the only drunken tattoo he brought home.
馬丁
是個
傻逼
你能把這個紋身給蓋掉嗎
Would you be able to cover something like that?
天哪
Oh, my God!
還有這個
And that one there.
傻逼
別問我這個是怎么搞上去的
Don't ask me why I had that one done, like.
這里還有一個
I got that one over there.
這是泰恩賽德人的一句俗語
It's a Geordie saying.
絕他媽不作施尼夫塔
"Not a fucking Shniffta."
帶把兒的純爺們
旅行中的
男孩們
阿依納帕
像馬特這類人  他們喜歡喝酒
People like Matt, they like a drink.
喜歡聚會  玩嗨了以后就毫無原則
They party, and all common sense goes out the window
只要有個紋身師傅在
and there's a tattooist there
基本是想紋啥就紋啥
willing to sort of do anything they want.
腿上有一個  這還一個
One on my leg there, another there.
那些罵人的話  我們不會去紋
And all the swearwords... I mean, we wouldn't do that,
但在國外就可以
but it's something that they'll have done abroad.
腿上紋的是"一夜情的產物"
"Product of a one night stand," on my leg.
我屁股上還紋了你的名字
Your name tattooed on my arse.
看來我們得花上一整年啊
Well, we've got 12 months' work then, haven't we?
確實不少
Quite a few!
我愛紋身
Yeah, I love tattoos.
我覺得很棒
I think they're fabulous.
不管誰紋身都很帥  真的
Whoever come up with them is awesome, to be honest.
馬特決定用一只巨鷹的圖案
Matt's decided to cover his tattoo
把紋身蓋住
with a picture of a giant eagle.
你想把鷹的翅膀放在這個位置是吧
Because you want the wings sort of up over here and there.
是的
Yeah.
準備好了嗎
Are you ready?
干  好疼
God! Fuck, that hurts!
馬特最近的十四個紋身
Matt got his last 14 tattoos
都是在阿伊納帕喝醉后紋的
while drunk in Ayia Napa.
阿伊納帕是個好地方
Ayia Napa's a great place to be.
我原計劃去那待兩周  感受下派對氣氛
I went out for a fortnight holiday for a party atmosphere.
迷人的沙灘海景
Brilliant sand, brilliant sea, brilliant sand,
還有大胸和美臀  太爽了
tits and arse - ideal.
我就干脆把票一撕住下了
So I ripped my ticket up and just stayed out there.
心想  去你妹的威爾士  雨下個沒完
Said, "Stuff it! Fuck Wales in the rain!"
但即使回到這里
But even back in the valleys,
馬特也不為那些紋身感到羞恥
Matt's not ashamed of his Napa tattoos.
很多時候
I mean, a lot of the times,
我到了一個新地方
if I'm at new places and that,
談到紋身的時候
till the subject of tattoos is brought up,
就會說  我這也有紋身
I say, "Look at this for a tattoo!"
然后脫掉上衣給他們看
and I take my top off and show them my tattoos
他們就會非常吃驚
and they're like, "Fucking hell!"
還可以拿紋身和女孩搭訕
For girls, it breaks the ice.
把她們逗樂  后面的事你懂的
It gets them giggling and talking and then...you know the rest.
我連當時自己在哪兒都想不明白了
It took me a while to realise where I was then!
-這是怪獸嗎  -這個得花40小時
- Beast? - 40 hours, that.
40小時
40?
給我紋那個40分鐘就能搞定
Could have done that on mine in 40 minutes.
我的估計40秒就搞定了
Could have done that on mine in 40 fucking seconds, I think!
第一部分搞定了
The first session's over.
今天就先弄到這吧
All right, I'm going to leave it at that, I think.
但是馬特還需要
But Matt's going to need
再過來做幾次才能最終完成
several more sittings with Dave to finish the job.
不錯
Yeah.
我喜歡這個  相當簡潔有力
I like that. That's tidy, isn't it?
與馬特不同  39歲的卡爾·麥考恩
Unlike Matt, 39 year-old Carl Mccoid
做紋身還不是很久
is relatively new to tattoos...
你好啊  最近怎么樣
Hiya, you all right?
他一年前才做了第一個紋身
Having only got his first one just over a year ago.
妹子  今天衣服不多嘛
Ah, nice one. You haven't got much today.
卡爾在家做清洗熨燙衣服的工作
Carl runs his cleaning and ironing business from home.
幸虧你今天帶來的衣服不多
Yeah, so, I'm glad you didn't bring much, actually,
我下午還有其他事
because I'm needing my afternoon free.
你下午準備干嘛
So what you doing this afternoon?
再去紋個身
Getting another tattoo done.
不是吧  今天
What, today?
是滴
Yeah!
-又要紋身  -對
- Another one? - Yeah.
你紋得還不夠多么
Are you sure you've not already got enough done?
不知道  雖然我覺得該紋的都紋了
I don't know, I've got like, as much as I wanted to get done,
可就是有這種感覺
but I don't know, I just feel like
我得再紋一個
I just needed another one done.
每次我一聽她的音樂就有這種沖動
Every time I listen to her music, I just get this impulse.
最初我是從聽第一電臺開始的
It started when I was listening to Radio 1
那個臺經常放《再次與你相見》
playing See You Again quite a lot,
我當時就想
I was thinking
她就是《漢娜·蒙塔娜》里那個女孩
Ah, it's that girl from Hannah Montana.
*我  我迫不及待*
*Oh, I, I can't wait*
*想見到你*
*to see you again... *
我想看看這個女孩長什么樣
And I thought, "I'd love to see what this girl looks like,
這個想法不錯
"This is brilliant,"
于是我買了張她的專輯
so I bought the album
然后我很快就被她吸引住了
and that got me instantly fixed.
他以前跟他的妻子一起做這個生意
He used to run the business with his wife,
但三年前他們離婚了
but they separated three years ago.
離婚讓我失去了很多東西
From the divorce, something really took off
包括麥莉·塞勒斯
with the Miley Cyrus thing.
我很低落
I got really down.
心想  我要怎么辦  我還有三個孩子
I thought, "How am I going to cope? I've got three kids,"
突然之間  我只剩孤身一人了
and all of a sudden, I'm on my own.
我紋了第一個紋身后  事情有了改觀
Things started to change when I got the first tattoo.
那是我人生的轉折點
That was my turning point,
我意識到我可以更接近這個人
I realised I could get closer to this person,
和這種激情
this passion,
就在那時我找到
and that's when I started to find
一種新的幸福
a new-found happiness.
我相信麥莉·塞勒斯填補了某些東西
And I believe that Miley Cyrus has kind of filled something,
很難說清楚
I'm not sure what.
那種感覺很美妙
It feels pretty good, yeah.
這是我紋的第一處麥莉·塞勒斯
The first one I had Miley Cyrus
之后我決定
and then I decided, right,
我要把麥莉·塞勒斯紋在手指上
I need Miley Cyrus on my fingers now,
讓別人都能看得到
because I need to show this,
然后我想  來都來了
and I said, while you're there,
順便紋兩處她的簽名吧
can I have her signature?
然后我就紋了兩個她的簽名
So I've got two signatures.
我越來越沉溺于她的音樂
I was getting deeper and deeper into the music,
《不可馴服》這張專輯發行以后
This Can't Be Tamed album,
我在顯眼的地方紋了"不可馴服"
so I obviously got Can't Be Tamed
和"自由行走"
and Liberty Walk,
后者是這張專輯里我最喜歡的歌
which is my favourite song off that album
自由同時意味著
and liberty also means
毫不拘束地表達自己的愛
freedom to express...to express my love,
因此我紋了"自由行走"
hence Liberty Walk.
她的歌里我最喜歡的是"著魔"
My favourite song of hers is Obsessed.
又一個雙關語
Double meaning again.
對她著魔
Obsessed with her.
#我是否對你著了魔#
# Am I obsessed with you? #
與此同時我還紋了"脫逃"
So I had that done at the same time as Breakout.
同樣一語雙關
Double meaning as well.
逃離過去  迎接現在全新的生活
Breakout of my old life to this new life.
于是我說  都到這份子上了
And I just said, while you're there,
能不能幫我在后脖紋上"麥莉"
can you just put "Miley" on the back of my neck?
然后我就在脖后紋上了這個
So I had Miley done on the back of my neck.
還有這個"永遠的十二月"
The other one's Permanent December,
也是一個雙關語
the double meaning again.
以前我和家人總在圣誕節時出去旅行
Me and my family used to go away for Christmas holidays
總有一些東西
and it was always something
讓我們無法離家而去
we never used to want to come home from.
和家人在一起的時候就像永遠的十二月
And it used to be, like, kind of a Permanent December.
我希望永遠留住這樣的日子
I'd want to be there permanently.
很奇怪  我真的不懂
It's weird, because I can't really
人們為什么會覺得我的行為很極端
understand peoples' reactions, why they think it's extreme,
因為我不這樣認為
because I don't think it is.
我覺得這就像是
I think it's just kind of like...
一種獻身  你明白吧
it's dedication, really, you know what I mean?
你為什么不直接去美國
Why don't you just go over to America
看她的現場表演呢
and go and see her in a show?
我沒法跟她面對面或者親眼去見她
I couldn't possibly be face to face with her or see her.
我會激動死的  你懂吧
I'd die. You know what I mean?
真是難以置信  卡爾
I can't believe that, Carl!
我會興奮過度的
I'd feel...it's too much.
我認識卡爾有七年了
I've known Carl for seven years.
如果我現在才偶然認識他
If I met him now out of the blue,
我應該不會請他
he's not somebody I'd probably choose
來我家幫我打掃房間
to come and clean my house for me,
但是因為我認識他很久了
but because I've known him so long,
我了解真正的卡爾是什么樣的
it's like I know the real Carl.
我懷疑過我是否神志清醒
I have questioned my sanity,
但是我越思考這個問題  我越發現
but the more and more I think about it, I think,
這真的讓我很快樂  我自己也難以相信
no, this is actually making me so happy, it's unbelievable.
我體驗到從未有過的快樂
Happiness that I've never felt before.
換做是我  我不會紋那么多
If I was you, I wouldn't have any more done.
-不會嗎  -不會  你紋得夠多了
- Wouldn't you? - No, you've got enough.
-真的嗎  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
每次見我母親時  她總會用一種
When I see my mum, she kind of like looks at me,
很擔心的眼神看我
she's really worried about it, actually.
這你不能怪她
Well, I don't blame her, actually.
你的狀態就像你胳膊上紋得一樣
Well, you are, as you say on your arm,
仿佛是著魔了  對吧
it's like obsessed, isn't it?
很難說清  別人可能會以為
I don't know, just as if you might be
你正在經歷中年危機
going through a bit of a midlife crisis.
真的嗎  我暈  什么狗屁中年危機
Really? Bloody hell! Midlife crisis, God!
我承認  她說的有些話讓我驚訝
I must admit, I was surprised by some of the stuff she said,
尤其是那句中年危機
especially when she said, midlife crisis.
人們會這樣想嗎
Is that what people are thinking?
對我來說這很正常
To me it's just normal.
我只是喜歡紋身  紋的是我喜歡的東西
It's just something that I'm doing and it's something that I love.
等我紋好這一個以后  我可能會想著
So when I get this tattoo done, I'll be thinking,
這是最后一個了吧  可露西說了
I'll make this the last one. Lucy says, right...
得了吧  怎么可能
Please, your last one!
這些言論沒有改變我的任何想法
It's not turned me in any way
或是讓我再重新考慮
into having second thoughts or anything like that.
我只會覺得  人們就是這種反應
I just think, oh, right, that's the reaction.
可以理解
All right, that's fair enough.
那好吧  再見
All right then, see you later.
-回見  -拜
- OK, yeah. - Bye.
在伯明翰的尖矛工作室
In Spear Studio, Birmingham,
芙蘭·貝利是那里的常客
one of their regulars, Fran Bailey,
她大老遠從威爾士的新市鎮過來
has come all the way from New Town, Wales
想進一步完善她的獨特設計
for some more work on her unique project.
我剛剛失去今年的第五只貓咪
I've just lost my fifth cat in a year
于是我將它們的畫像紋在自己的背上
and I'm having their portraits put on my back.
我愛貓勝過一切
I love cats more than anything.
貓咪是最美好的生靈
Cats are the bestest thing.
不是狗  我和別人的想法不同
Not dogs, like other people seem to think.
面朝那邊可以嗎
Do you want to face that way?
可以
Ah, yes.
我希望我的貓咪與眾不同
I wanted something that was a bit different with my cats,
展現出它們的個性
and showed off their personalities.
中間的斯波克先生總是弄傷自己
Mr Spock, he's in the middle and he was always hurting himself,
它渾身貼滿繃帶
so he's got loads of bandages all over him.
刷子先生戴單片眼鏡系著領結
Mr Brush has got a monocle and a bow tie,
因為它是典型的英倫紳士
because he was a very English gentleman,
但是它其實試圖統治世界
but he was also set on world domination.
還有汀琪  它是我的寶貝
There's Tinky, who was my baby.
如果我是只貓咪  又是拉拉的話
If I was a cat and a lesbian,
它就是我的真名天喵
that would be the cat for me.
我要嫁給這只喵
I'd marry that cat.
我好愛這只貓咪
I loved that cat so much.
芙蘭找到了綜合這兩種愛好的方法
And Fran's found a way of combining both her passions.
天哪  看起來好亮眼  一級棒
Oh my god! It looks so bright! That's ace!
只有一點點地方需要重做
Just got little bits to redo at some point,
這里  還有這里
like there and up here.
在她父母的家里
Back at her parents' house,
芙蘭將她的舊臥室改裝成了紋身工作室
Fran's converted her old bedroom into a tattoo studio of her own.
歡迎來到幸運貓咪紋身藝術工作室
Welcome to Lucky Kitty Tattoo Arts!
我喜歡畫畫
Yeah, I've always drawn
也很鐘情紋身藝術
and I've always been interested in tattoo art,
我去當過學徒  掌握了這門技術
so I went for an apprenticeship and I got it.
但想在繁華街區的工作室里當個全職紋身師
But with full-time places in high street studios
變得越來越困難
increasingly hard to find,
芙蘭作為一個新手紋身師
Fran's part of a new breed of tattooist,
只能在家中開設工作室
setting up at home.
我真的毫無名氣
I'm a no-name, really,
所以我需要一些東西吸引他人注意
and I needed something, you know, to stand out.
工作室名字朗朗上口  容易令人記住
And it's sort of a mouthful. So you sort of remember it.
幸運貓咪紋身藝術工作室
Lucky Kitty Tattoo Arts.
雖然是個新手
Although a relative beginner,
她每小時收費已達到三十英鎊
she's already charging 30 pounds an hour.
一切都很順利
It's going really well,
因為我為顧客提供了與眾不同的東西
because I think I offer something different.
從大的方面看來沒什么不同
I mean, nothing different in the grand scheme of things,
但在我們鎮上還是獨特的
but in our town.
在家里開設工作室
And having a studio in their house
對她父母產生了深遠的影響
has made a definite impression on her parents.
雖然我的眼睛沒以前好使了
Although my eyes aren't what they used to be,
但是還是很漂亮  蒂奇
that's very nice, Titch.
現在我也想在背后紋個仙女了
I want a fairy on my back now!
紋身這東西很奇怪
It's a strange thing,
我已經讓她給我紋了兩個了
I've actually had two now of her,
這事放在以前我想都不會想
which I would never have thought about before.
我從來不覺得自己會去紋身
It would never have occurred to me to have a tattoo.
芙蘭手藝很棒
Yeah, Fran is good. She's, er...
我也許有點偏心
Well, I might be biased,
不過我應該偏心的  我是她爸呀
I will be biased, I'm her dad,
所有被她紋過的人
but all the people that she has done a tattoo for,
都非常滿意
they've all been very, very pleased.
接下來  芙蘭要給她爸爸雷設計一個新紋身
Next, Fran's going to design a new tattoo for her dad, Ray.
我都這把年紀了
With my age now,
不知道還能活多少日子
I don't know how long more I'm going to be lasting for,
我的紋身情結
至少能給她一塊練習的畫布
but at least she's had a canvas to practise on!
我的紋身情結
阿伊  阿伊  阿伊丫的納帕
Ayia, Ayia, Ayia fucking Napa.
對很多英國青年來說
For many young Brits,
出國是他們紋身的第一個機會
their first opportunity to get a tattoo is abroad.
每年夏天  阿伊納帕的紋身工作室里
And during the summer, Ayia Napa's tattoo studios
總會擠滿了飲酒作樂的游客
are filled with revellers,
渴望著他們的第一個紋身
keen for their first taste of ink.
你紋的這些很不錯
You do a lot of good stuff.
這些紋身都很漂亮
You know, you get good sorts like this, you get nice stuff,
不過你也還有很多傻乎乎的小修改要做
and you get loads of the silly, little things to do as well.
給我來顆小愛心
I want a little love heart.
沒問題
Yeah, little bits.
阿伊納帕  寶貝
Ayia Napa, baby.
納帕就是一座瘋人院  毫不夸張
Napa is a madhouse, that's what it is.
上面紋著"杰克和凱莉"
It says, "Jack and Kelly,"
那是她認識的一個男孩
that's some random boy that she met.
我和他才認識了一分鐘
I'd known him for one minute.
她有個交往了兩年的男友  結果他把她甩了
And she'd had a boyfriend for two years then he's finished her.
-太有趣了  -太無聊了
- Well funny. - Well boring.
-太無聊了  -太無聊了
- Well boring. - Well boring.
在這兒你肯定會去搞一個醉酒紋身的
You've definitely got to get a drunken tattoo while you're here.
凯斯
夜店代表
我紋了兩個
I mean, I've got two.
屁股兩邊各有一個  腳趾上有一個
I've got one on both arse cheeks, I've got one on my toe...
我這里有一盒小的紋身樣式
I've got a box full of bits
保 羅
血色兄弟紋身室
我們常常紋這些東西  都是常規的樣式
and these are the sort of things that we do, standard stuff.
嘴唇什么的  我每天能紋二十個
Lips, I can do 20 of them a day.
他把我的唇印紋在了他的屁股上
He's getting my lips on his bum.
這個也很流行
This is a popular one,
把"阿伊納帕2012"紋在屁股上
Ayia Napa 2012 on the bum.
一抓一大把
Usual shit.
人們一來這兒  就會把人名紋在屁股上
People come here, they get people's names written on their arse,
我的一個朋友把"綠隊"紋在了胸口
one of my friends had Team Green written on his chest.
"綠隊"  這叫什么意思
I mean, Team Green, what's that all about?
太爛了
Just rubbish.
我們紋的這個也很流行
The stuff we do that's so popular, it's...
這個是拉丁語的
This stuff as well, this is Latin.
拉丁語紋身
Latin stuff.
快看她  她紋了活在夢中
It was her. She is living the dream!
活在夢中
[拉丁語]
我真的活在夢里啦
I am living the dream!
我在納帕  簡直和做夢一樣
I'm in Napa, I'm having a dream.
還有人紋一些傻里傻氣的話
Silly quotes, you know, like,
比如"要么努力要么回家"或是"熱愛生活"
"Go hard or go home" or "Loving life".
還有  不論哪年都有人紋2012
You know, whatever the year is, 2012.
機靈點兒  伙計
"Stay schemin',son."
我腳邊的就紋的這個
That's the tattoo you can see there.
來了納帕  人人都會犯傻去搞個紋身
Come to Napa, everyone gets a silly tattoo.
我和我朋友一起來的  這會有點喝多了
And I'm with my friends, but I'm a little bit drunk,
但愿別太糟糕
so hopefully it won't be too bad.
你好啊  疼痛
Hello, pain.
你從哪里來的呀
Where'd you come from?
我一直想要個紋身
I've always wanted a tattoo.
不過不是這樣的
I've not always wanted one like this,
可我還是紋了
but things happen,
但愿我老了以后別后悔
hopefully I won't regret it when I'm older.
我肯定不會后悔
I'm pretty sure I won't.
機靈點兒
"Stay schemin'"!
像這些很特別的句子
There are some really...different sayings,
每年都會層出不窮
every year there's always something else.
機靈點兒  伙計
"Stay schemin'", pal.
我不知道它們出自哪里
I don't know where they come from,
但我們每天都在紋  挺有趣的  不是嗎
but we do them all day. They're funny, you know?
安全
Safety!
這個生意很有賺頭
Yeah, it's very good business.
標準收費是四十歐元
It's about...standard charge for that is 40 Euro.
幾周前我接待了一個十七個人的團隊
I had a group of 17 a couple of weeks ago.
只花了一個半小時左右
It takes an hour, hour and a half.
十七個人  賺了一大筆錢
17 people, that's good money.
燕子  這個今年很流行
Swallow, they're really popular this year.
我的朋友們都紋了燕子  所以...
All my mates got a swallow, so...
所有的小伙伴們都紋了燕子
My best mates... Everyone's getting a swallow.
我祖父曾在海軍服役  他胳膊上就有了一個
My granddad was in the Navy and he's got one on his arm.
還因為我們就在阿伊納帕
And because we're in Ayia Napa.
沒錯
Yeah.
來吧  快點  繼續紋吧
Go on, crack on. I'll let you crack on.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我真想一直盯著它看
Oh, I don't want to stop looking at it.
我剛紋了我的第一個紋身
I just got my first tattoo!
顯然  它將伴隨你一生
Obviously, it's going to be on you for the rest of your life,
與此同時  它也是一份記憶
but at the same time, it's a memory.
我不想回家
I don't want to go home.
機靈點兒  伙計
"Stay schemin'...son."
我覺得他們不會后悔
I don't think they regret it.
大家都在紋身
It's just a group thing.
年輕人來這里度假
Young people away on holiday
縱情玩樂
and just enjoying themselves.
對他們來說  這是難忘的回憶
You know, to them it's a memory.
看到我的紋身了嗎
Can you see mine?
看見了
Yeah, yeah.
這是我的第一個紋身
It were my first tattoo
今年我要在阿伊納帕再紋一個
and I'm getting another one this year in Ayia Napa.
你要紋什么
What are you getting?
沒想好
I don't know.
也許會紋"納帕"
Probably "Napa".
阿伊  阿伊  阿伊丫的納帕
Ayia, Ayia, Ayia fucking Napa.
回到魔咒紋身店
Back at Abracadabra Tattoos...
我挺喜歡你給我紋的老鷹
Yeah I do quite like how you've done it.
很高興你能喜歡
Glad about that.
如果我這樣動  它還可以飛呢
If I go like that, it can fly as well.
戴夫起了個大早
It's an early start for Dave,
幫馬特蓋住他的阿伊納帕紋身
covering up Matt's Ayia Napa tattoo.
說實話  我有點惡心
I feel quite sick now, to be honest.
這可不是個好的開始
This is not starting well, is it?
抱歉
Pardon me.
準備好了嗎
Ready?
好了
Yep.
對于馬特來說  蓋住他的紋身
For Matt, getting his tattoos covered up
不只是為了美觀
isn't just about aesthetics.
你看這是什么
What's this, then?
回到威爾士后  他成了一個父親
Since his return to Wales, he's become a father.
躲貓貓
Peek-a-boo!
我身上很多紋身都是臟話
Cos I've got a lot of bad language tattooed on me now,
馬丁
是個
傻逼
我的孩子出生后
as soon as my kids come along,
我想  是時候把它蓋住了
I thought, "Well, it's time to go and cover it up, like,"
這是為她好
for her benefit.
不僅如此  在公共場所游泳也是個大問題
Not only that, it's hard to go swimming in public places.
我太太想讓我
My missus wants me to
紋一個迪士尼公主給我女兒
have a Disney princess done for my daughter,
這可不行
but that's not happening.
她不怎么喜歡鷹
She doesn't really like the eagles,
但我喜歡  而這是我的身體  不是她的
but I do, but it's my body not hers,
所以我決定先紋上
so I'll have it done
紋好以后再看她怎么說
and just see what she says after it's done, innit?
今天坐得很老實啊  馬特
Had a good sitting today, Matt.
之前的紋身全蓋住了
We've covered the lot, you know.
咱們的工夫沒白費
We haven't messed about, like.
好了  就到這兒吧
Yeah, I'm going to leave it at that, I think.
馬特只需再等幾周
Matt will need to wait a few weeks
待皮膚愈合  就可以進行最后的處理
for his skin to heal before his final session.
我喜歡  非常喜歡
Yeah, I like that. Very much.
在約克郡的布里德靈頓
In Bridlington, Yorkshire,
卡爾·麥考恩正準備
Carl McCoid is getting
紋第十六個麥莉·塞勒斯紋身
his 16th Miley Cyrus tattoo.
這是你的紋身模板  伙計
Here's your stencil, mate.
挺好看的  真不錯
Ah, nice one. Yeah, that's smart, innit.
他來到黑燈籠紋身工作室
He's come to Black Lantern Studios
找他的專屬紋身師  斯圖爾特
to see his regular tattooist, Stuart.
營業中
黑燈籠紋身工作室
好了  卡爾  開始吧
All right, Carl, here we go.
好的
Right.
當你習慣了你的紋身  你就會想
You get used to your tattoo, so you think,
我得再紋一個
"Ah, I need to get another one..."
因為實在還有太多皮膚可以紋身了
"Because I'm feeling there's a bit too much skin going on," you know.
紋身能讓你放松
It does give you a relief.
讓你自我感覺更好
It makes you feel so much better about yourself,
就像是買了新褲子或是新T恤
just like when you get a new pair of jeans or t-shirt, whatever,
你感覺很好  因為它是新的
you feel good about it, you know, it's new.
紋身也是這樣
And, yeah, it's like that with a tattoo.
斯圖爾特很清楚卡爾的愛好
Stuart is no stranger to Carl's obsession.
如果喜歡麥莉·塞勒斯有一個限度的話
I think if there was a line with Miley Cyrus,
他絕對是鐵桿粉絲
it's been crossed.
不過只要自己高興就好了
But, you know, whatever floats your boat.
還有人要紋凱蒂貓之類的東西呢
I mean, people get covered in Hello Kitty and stuff like that.
我搞不懂
I don't get that.
每個人紋身的原因各有不同
There's a lot of reasons why people get tattoos,
但那是他們自己的決定
but it's their own reasons so, you know,
我們憑什么質疑呢
who are we to question that?
如果我們不紋或者紋的不好
If we don't do it and don't do a good job,
他們會到街上找別家紋身店來做
they'll just go down the street and get someone else to do it.
不過是喜歡麥莉·塞勒斯罷了
You know, it's Miley Cyrus.
又能傷害到誰呢
Who's it offending, really?
他沒傷害到誰
He's not hurting anybody.
對吧
You know?
如果我要開始一段感情
If ever I wanted a relationship again,
我最不能忽視的一點就是
which obviously I can't rule that out,
她一定要是麥莉·塞勒斯的粉絲
she'd have to be a Miley Cyrus fan.
麥莉·塞勒斯占據我生活的絕大部分
Miley Cyrus is a massive part of my life,
感情可能也只能排在第二
so a relationship would probably come second.
卡爾已經開始構思他的下一個紋身了
And Carl's already thinking about his next tattoo.
這些紋身大部分是源于上一張專輯
Most of all these tattoos are, like, from the last album,
現在她又發了新專輯
the new album's got to come out yet.
這樣就會有各式各樣的
There's going to be all sorts of, like...
圖案可以隨意挑選了
cherry picking to do off that.
那話怎么說來著
What's that saying again?
我已然出發
"I've started now...
并將繼續前進
"..Carry on."
如果你愛一個人就會想讓全世界都知道
If you love somebody, you want the whole world to know.
你不想也不需要遮遮掩掩的
You're not going hide it, you've got nothing to hide
這樣的愛與熱情不需要隱藏
when you've got this love and a passion.
我的工作完成了
My work here is done.
我擔心的是這種感覺會消失
What I am worried about is if this ever goes away.
或是這種癡迷會離我而去
I am kind of scared that this obsession might just leave me,
我很害怕麥莉·塞勒斯會離開觀眾的視線
I'm scared that Miley Cyrus might disappear from the scene...
這些才是我害怕的
That's the fear I have.
這是我想要的生活
This is what I want for life,
因為這一切讓我真正感到快樂
because this has genuinely made me happy.
棒極了  是不是
Yeah, it's brilliant, innit?
我的紋身情結
在康沃爾郡的圣奧斯特爾
In St Austell, Cornwall,
24歲的奧斯丁·帕里認為自己紋身成癮
24-year-old Austin Parry is a self-confessed tattoo addict.
我有十四個紋身
I've got about 14 tattoos.
我不知道到底為什么會喜歡它們
I don't really know what got me into them.
可能那時候朋友和家人會去紋身
I think it's friends and family getting them done at the time,
特別是年輕時出去玩兒
and obviously when you're young, hanging around,
喜歡裝酷
you want to be cool 'and,
實際上  一旦你開始紋身就停不下來
literally, once you pop,you can't stop.'
我對紋身上癮  我就是很沉迷
I'm addicted to them and I just love tattoos.
你好
Hello, you all right?
我的回頭率確實很高
'I definitely get a few looks.
有時我都忘了自己頭上有紋身
'Sometimes I forget I've got tattoos on my head,
我習慣了  因為自己也不是常能看到
I'm so used to it.' You can't always see them all the time.
你會奇怪  他為什么老盯著你看
You think, "What the hell is he staring at?"
之后才意識到自己的臉上有個蝎子
Then you realise there's a scorpion down the side of your face.
-給你  -好的
-There you go. - Lovely,
-謝謝你  -謝謝
- Thank you. - Thank you.
今天他要去見當地的紋身師羅德
Today, he's meeting his local tattooist, Rod,
討論如何遮蓋前女友的名字
about covering up an ex-girlfriend's name.
嗨  伙計
Hello, mate.
你好  羅德  最近還好嗎
Hello. You all right, Rod?
你好嗎  伙計
You all right, bud?
最近怎么樣
How's it going?
還可以  伙計
Not too bad, man.
太好了
Good, good.
我看今天還是要紋蝎子  對嗎
I take it it's the scorpion today then, yeah?
是啊  伙計
Yes, mate, it is.
我覺得會比較簡單
I think it'll be pretty straightforward.
就在去年
Only last year,
羅德才遮蓋了奧斯丁一側
Rod covered up a tattoo of the
脖子上的那個名字梅麗莎
name Melissa on the other side of Austin's neck.
我女朋友認識我脖子上寫的這個姑娘
My partner knows the girl who was on here before,
所以她讓我把名字遮蓋
so she decided to get it covered up.
是她非要我遮蓋的
Well, I got told to cover it up,
可以這么說嗎
should I say?
這邊也是一樣的
And it's the same with this one as well,
這是另一個前任
it's another ex,
她不希望我身上再有其他名字
so she just doesn't want any other names on me.
她不想再被誤認為是黛西
She don't want to get mistaken for being Daisy?
是的  絕對不想
No, definitely not.
是的  她不接受這個
No, that doesn't go down too well.
黛西是我在
Daisy was an ex,
在普利茅斯時的前女友
it was up in Plymouth.
我花了整整五英鎊紋這個紋身
It actually cost me ￡5 to get that tattoo done,
我自己喜歡紋身也是因素之一
Yes, it was a spur of a moment thing there and then as well.
我不想錯過任何紋身的機會
I didn't want to miss out on the opportunity of a tattoo.
事實上  我紋完的第二天她就跟我分手了
She actually split up with me the day after I got it done.
分手原因雖然跟紋身無關
Had nothing to do with the tattoo,
不過她確實是第二天就跟我分手了
but yeah, she split up with me the day after,
所以我只能盡快
so I got it covered up...well,
把它遮蓋住
as soon as I could.
哪個  梅麗莎還是黛西
What, Melissa or Daisy?
兩個都是
Both.
黛西是第一個
Oh, Daisy was the first.
另一邊才是黛西
Daisy's that one.
是哦  黛西在這邊才對
Oh, yeah. Daisy's that one, isn't it?
黛西的名字還沒蓋過呢
I haven't even got Daisy covered up yet.
并不是所有人都能理解
But not everyone understands why Austin
為什么奧斯丁這么熱衷于在臉上紋身
is so keen to have another tattoo on his face.
明天你有什么安排嗎
What are you doing tomorrow?
我要去紋身
I'm getting a tattoo done.
又要紋身啊
Oh, not another one.
是  再紋一個蝎子
Yep, another scorpion.
不是吧  為什么啊
Oh, no. Why?
遮蓋這一側最后一個名字
Cover up the last name on the side there.
不能紋點別的圖案嗎
Can't it be something different?
一定要在臉上
Does it have to be...
再紋一個可怕的圖案嗎
that monstrosity that's on your face?
好吧  他們可以紋個不帶鉗子的蝎子
Oh, yeah, they could do a scorpion without a claw,
不過看起來會很蠢吧
but it'd look silly, really.
我擔心他會后悔
I worry that he'll regret it.
他已經后悔紋了那些名字
Well, I think he's already regretted having the names,
人們去紋身的時候
but I think when they have them done,
沒意識到那些圖案是永久的
I don't think they realise they're there forever,
結果紋完以后  就去不掉了
and once they've got them, that's it.
即使是奧斯丁的妻子薩姆
Even Austin's partner, Sam,
也不愿他再去紋一只蝎子
is in two minds about his plan to get another scorpion.
我不太喜歡他臉上的紋身
I don't really like the ones on his face...
可我又想叫他把那些名字遮蓋掉
..but, obviously, I want them covered up,
我就是覺得圖案有點兒大
but I just think they're a bit big.
別人會因為他的紋身議論他嗎
Do people judge him because he's got tattoos?
當然了
Oh, god, yeah.
在商店的時候  人們會跟著我們
We'll be in a shop and the people will follow us round,
盯著看
stare,
看他是不是會偷東西什么的
seeing if he's going to nick anything or something.
布魯克  你喜歡奧斯丁的紋身嗎
Brooke, do you like Austin's tattoos?
-喜歡  -真的嗎
- Yeah. - You do?
是的
Yeah.
為什么呢
Why?
因為我喜歡它們
Because I like them.
是嗎
Do you?
它們很好看
They're pretty.
你會想要紋身嗎
Are you going to have some?
會呀
Yeah.
作為一個個體油漆工和室內裝潢師
As a self-employed painter and decorator,
奧斯丁不用擔心他的紋身會影響他的工作機會
Austin isn't concerned his tattoos might limit his opportunities.
紋身前我不會
I never sit there and
多想紋完以后會怎么樣
think about the future before I get one done.
我不會去想象自己老了的樣子
I can't really picture myself being old,
沒有任何意義
if that makes any sense.
我無法想象自己到老了還滿臉紋身
I can't see myself being that old with tattoos on my head,
即使我已經紋了
even though I've got them,
不過就現在而言
but as for today,
我依然為之高興
I'm glad I've got them done
并且還想再紋一個
and I'm glad I'm getting a new one done.
日式庭院很迷人
Japanese gardens are lovely.
67歲的雷跟他的妻子薩莉
67-year-old Ray lives with his wife, Sally,
還有他們的八只貓生活在威爾士的紐鎮
and their eight cats in Newtown, Wales.
如果我有錢
If I had the money,
我會挖一條小河
it would be a little stream,
在上面造幾座小橋
those little bridges they got over it,
那會是一片美麗的圣地
a shrine here and things like that, lovely.
我很喜歡這些
I'd love it.
很適合老年人生活休憩
Yeah, somewhere to relax in the old age.
這小花園里埋葬著幾只貓
There's a couple of our poor cats
我讓它們長眠于此
that we've had to be put to sleep there,
就在埋在這里
underneath there,
所以這也是個很棒的小紀念館
so it's a nice little memorial to them, that.
拉斯基在那邊
Laskie there.
還有可憐的小根格斯
And poor little Genghis is just there as well.
可惜我沒法擴建這個花園
So, yeah, it's a shame we haven't got it bigger,
但物盡其用就夠了  對吧
but you've got to make do with what you got, innit?
紋身一直是雷生活中的一部分
Tattoos have always been a part of Ray's life.
我第一次紋身是1962年
The first one I ever had was in 1962,
那個周六下午我就跑去打橄欖球
but I played rugby on the Saturday afternoon,
弄得渾身都是污泥
the day after, and I got it covered in mud
結果第二天剛紋好的手臂大面積感染
and my hand come up here with the infection.
今天  我要紋一個...
Today, i'm having...
好像叫般若還是波若的圖案
I think they're called hannya or hatya,
是一種日本面具
and it's a Japanese mask.
我女兒已經設計好了圖
My daughter's designed it,
其實我是想遮住這些的
but that's a cover-up for these here.
這是過去白人盎格魯-撒克遜新教徒的標志
It's the old White Anglo-Saxon Protestant.
WASP原義是指美國的新教上流社會
即殖民時期來自英國的移民
那個年代  在美國
At that time, in the country, there was...
任何地方都不允許掛圣喬治十字旗
We couldn't put Cross of St George's anywhere,
原英格蘭國旗
即使在英格蘭也不行
even in England.
我很憤怒  似乎沒人歡迎英格蘭人  對嗎
I was angry that no-one seemed to like the English, right?
然后我想  "好吧  別理他們"
So I thought, "Right, sod 'em."
可是沒有人知道它的意義
But no-one even knew what it meant.
我在醫院時
When I was in hospital,
有個護士問我它的意思
one of the nurses asked what it was for and I said,
我說意思是"我們是性愛狂魔"  如何
"We Are Sexual Predators," right?
然后她臨走時
And she went,
還答應了一聲  其實她不明白
"Oh." she didn't really know.
就是這樣的
You know, and that was it,
所以你可以這么說
so you could say it's that,
但意義卻并非如此
but it don't meant that.
這是一座極端種族主義
It means... It is really racist,
現在已經日漸消退
but that's coming off.
雷只需要下一小段樓梯
Ray just has a short walk downstairs
就到了他女兒芙蘭新開的紋身工作室
to his daughter Fran's new tattoo studio.
你準備好了嗎
You ready?
好了
Indeed.
先給你擦一擦
Let's scrub you down.
在我長大的地方
In the estates where I was brought up,
幾乎所有人都有紋身
nearly everyone has got tattoos.
有人在脖子這里紋過一條虛線
From...cut along the dotted line around here...
我有個朋友凱斯  他在下嘴唇里面
One of my mates, Keith, used to have his lip there,
紋了妻子的名字  上面是兩個孩子的名字
he had his wife there and his two kids tattooed in there.
人人都有紋身
Every other person was with a tattoo,
對此你就會見怪不怪了
and it's something that you get used to.
準備好了嗎  泰迪
Are you ready, teddy?
萬事俱備
As ready as I'm ever going to be.
好
Cool.
我要開始嘍
That'll do.
感覺怎么樣
How's that?
挺好的
'Tis fine, yeah.
那就好
'Tis fine.
我開始對日本產生興趣
I got interested in the Japanese things
是因為八十年代的一部名叫《幕府將軍》的劇
when they had a programme called The Shogun in the '80s.
我喜歡他們的文化
And I like the culture.
他們彬彬有禮
They're well-mannered.
你知道他們怎么鞠躬的嗎  很有意思
You know how they bow? Lovely stuff.
我不喜歡坐飛機
I don't like flying,
所以我沒法去日本
so if I can't go to Japan,
但我可以把日本風情帶來我家
I can bring Japan to me.
你在畫臉嗎  小貝
Are you doing the face now, babs?
-對  -好的
-Yes. -Right.
我父親以前跟現在判若兩人
My dad used to be very different to what he is today.
以前他對很多人心懷厭惡
He used to not really like many different sorts of people,
我覺得這些年他的態度改善了許多
and I think his attitude has changed a lot over the years,
現在他也羞于提及那些往事
and I think now it's something that he's quite ashamed of.
你承認自己曾是種族主義者嗎
So, would you say you were racist then?
當然了
Oh, definitely.
是的  那時我憎恨每一個人
Oh, yeah. We used to resent anyone at all.
不過還沒到去傷害別人的程度
Not through the fact that I'd hurt them or do anything like that.
英國最知名的極右翼政黨
反移民  反伊斯蘭教徒  反多元文化
我當時甚至還想加入英國國家黨的
I even was going to join the BNP once,
你可以想見我有多嚴重
that's how so severe it was.
你知道的
Well, you know that,
你也記得他們有多惡劣的吧
because you give me it terrible, didn't you?
那是確實是一段可怕的日子
Give me a terrible time, and quite rightly so.
我差點就不認你這個爸了
Almost disowned him.
有時你會感到很欣慰
Sometimes you're glad that
有個比你懂事的女兒
the daughter got more sense than you have,
我來算算我的種族主義觀念有多久了
but let's say I was a racist for...
從1996年開始...
From 1996...
我五十一歲的時候...前后九年
From... 51... ..Nine years,
但我不算很激進
but not an active...one.
當我意識到以前有多傻之后成熟多了
I mellowed when I realised what a prat I was being.
時代在改變  觀念也要跟上
Times have changed, attitudes change...
我很高興我能夠
..And I'm quite happy to...
與時俱進
Change with it.
很漂亮  芙蘭
That's lovely, fran.
居然用了這么多種顏色
I was surprised how much colour was in there.
-看上去好漂亮  -對啊
- It looks really good! - Yeah.
他喜歡五顏六色
He likes colour.
還能看到我的血  是嗎
And that's my blood, is it, that we can see?
對
Yeah.
大功告成
Da, da, da, da!
-完成了嗎  -搞定
- Is that finished, is it? - Yay!
太美了  芙蘭
That is superb, fran.
你覺得怎么樣  開心嗎
What do you think? Are you happy?
當然
I am.
-太贊了  -耶
- That is lovely. - Yay!
-我愛它  -不會太夸張嗎
- I love it. - You all right with it?
不會
I do.
我要帶著它進墳墓
When I die, i'm taking this with me.
遠在魔咒紋身店
Over at Abracadabra Tattoos,
戴夫·弗利特又有生意做了
Dave Fleet has another cover-up to do.
你想覆蓋什么
What have we got?
一個男人的名字
A man's name.
我要把它蓋住
Never have it done.
好的  坐下吧
Right, take a seat.
讓我看一下
Let me have a little look at that.
多恩·威廉姆斯有一個紋身
Dorne Williams has one tattoo
它時刻提醒著她的過去
which serves as a constant reminder
而她現在只想趕緊把它忘記
of a past she'd sooner forget.
我想在這下面
I think I'd like something
紋一朵華麗嬌柔的花
flowery and feminine down to about there.
-可以把這個留下  -對
- And we can keep this? - Yeah.
問題就只剩下伊安了
But the problem is Ian.
他確實是個該死的大問題
He was a bloody big problem!
伊安是誰
Who was Ian?
他是我丈夫
He was my husband who...buggered off
跟一個在臉書上認識的女人滾去美國了
to America with a woman he met on Facebook.
他當是度假呢
Well, he had a holiday out of it.
我就不表達意見了
I'm not saying anything.
多恩跟兒子住在附近的彭特紐德
Dorne lives with her son in nearby Pontnewydd.
這是我養的魚
And here's my fish.
這兩條天使魚
The two angel fish,
叫波什和貝克斯
Posh and Becks.
這只叫小抽抽
He's Twitch.
我也不知道為什么叫他小抽抽
I don't know why he's Twitch.
最近她與結婚四年的丈夫離婚了
Recently, she divorced her husband of four years.
他是我一生的摯愛
He was the love of my life.
我們是青梅竹馬
Childhood sweetheart,
二十多年后重逢
met him again after 20-odd years.
我們都墜入了愛河  我是這么想的
Both fell in love, as I thought.
我們同居了...
Within three months, four months,
三四個月
he was living with me.
我以為自己會永遠跟他在一起
I thought I'd be with him forever,
我當時在紋身店里
and...I was at the tattooist
背上的紋身才弄好一部分
actually having a bit done on my back
我突然決定紋上他的名字
and I just decided to have his name,
作為給他的驚喜
as a surprise, really,
我回到家
came home,
脫下衣服  露出他的名字
I took my dressing off and there was his name.
他哭了出來
He cried,
我也哭了
I cried.
那時我們都以為會彼此廝守到老
Just thought we were together forever.
大約一年后我們結婚了
A year or so into the marriage,
幸福在他離開的剎那崩塌
it all fell apart
我深受打擊
and it blew me apart.
我的整個世界支離破碎
It shattered my world.
這個紋身對我來說更像是傷疤
It's become more of a scar than a tattoo.
它比傷疤更傷人  只有除去它以后
It has become more of a scar and until that's gone,
我才能重新振作
I just can't move on.
你為什么不找另一個伊安呢
Why didn't you find another Ian?
因為我已經找了一個叫格林的了
Because I got one out there called Glyn.
-準備好了嗎  -好了
- Are you ready?  - Yep.
你第一次紋身是為什么
Why did you have your first tattoo?
因為你那時候在做慈善
Because you were doing it for charity.
多少年前了
How many years ago?
已經20年了吧  有嗎
Got to be 20, hasn't it?
你那時很瘦
You was skinny.
我現在還是很瘦
I'm still skinny.
拉倒吧  你才不是
Oh, fuck off, you ain't.
我記得我的第一個紋身
I remember the first tattoo I had,
是帶著我名字的圖案
a thing with my name on it.
我那時才十五歲
I was only 15,
我認為如果我有一個紋身
but I thought if I had a tattoo,
我就能混進酒吧
I could get in the pubs.
確實管用
It did work.
兒童不可入內
器物傷人
謝謝合作
每次我和我那位躺在床上
I'm in bed with the other half...
總能感覺到他在看這個紋身
I was self-conscious of him looking at it.
其實他也沒那么困擾
It didn't bother him that much.
過去人們說指著他說"這位肯定是伊安"
I mean, he used to laugh when people used to say,
他總是大笑
"Oh, this must be Ian."
但我覺得他心里肯定在想
But, deep down, I think he must thought,
"他媽的  誰敢再叫我伊安..."
"Oh, fucking hell, if one more person calls me Ian..."
紋身讓威爾士更美好
魔咒紋身工作室
現在我能取笑伊安那個王八蛋還真是好事
Well, it's a good job I can laugh about the old bastard.
好久沒笑過了
Never used to laugh.
老實說  過去三年對我來說就像地獄
I can honestly say, the last three years have been hell.
給我杯咖啡
我就不傷你
瞧  說得我都哽咽了
I've got a lump in my throat.
好生矯情
Soppy me, look.
這段感情就這樣散了
It's just gone.
我人生的那七八年也隨之而去了
That's seven, eight years of my life gone.
真的  你不知道
You don't know, really.
你不會懂那對我來說意味著什么
You really honestly have got no idea what that means to me.
好了
That's it.
全部搞定
All done.
非常感謝
Ah, thanks ever so much.
現在順眼多了
That's lush, that is.
來照一下鏡子
Have a look in the mirror.
現在他徹底消失了
He is now definitely gone.
我的天
Oh, my god!
幾乎都看不到了
You can't even see it!
親一個
Give me a kiss.
戴夫
Oh, Dave!
滿意嗎
All right?
太謝謝你了
Thank you so much.
那就好
Great.
乖孩子
Good girl.
這下好了
Nice one.
你挺過那段生活了
Part of your life done.
像蝴蝶般飛走了
Butterfly has flown.
這真是難以置信
Oh, it's fabulous!
我現在倍感輕松
It's just being free.
它真的一直困擾著我
It was haunting me, it really was.
謝謝  戴夫
Thanks, Dave.
我走了
I'm off now.
-好  -再見  謝謝戴夫
- Ok. - Bye, thanks Dave.
照顧好自己
Look after yourself.
好的
All right.
-再見  -再見
- Ta-ra. - Ta-ra now.
我的紋身情結
回到阿伊納帕  現在是一年最忙的時候
Back in Ayia Napa, it's the busiest time of the year
也是某樣事情最為流行的一個月
and a month especially popular for one thing.
七月是屁股月
July is an arse month.
季米特里奧斯: 皮膚紋身師
大多數都紋在屁股上
Most is on the arses,
紋一些有趣的小紋身
small, funny tattoos,
比如"阿伊納帕"和你的名字
Ayia Napa, your name.
他們總想說"我的屁股上紋著你的名字"
Also, they want "I have your name on my arse."
最受歡迎的地方就是屁股
Most popular place is the arse.
他想把我的名字紋在他的屁股上
He wants my name tattooed on his arse.
把你的名字紋在你的屁股上
Your name on your arse.
把他的名字紋在我屁股上
His name on my arse.
平常我不會想在屁股紋上
I don't generally want Luke Fisher, love heart,
盧克·費舍爾和愛心  但我不得不這樣做
tattooed on my arse, but...I've got to.
操你媽的  盧克
For fuck's sake, Luke.
在納帕玩大冒險
In the Napa games, right,
總會有人說  你敢嗎
if someone says call your bluff,
例如說  我敢在身上紋你的名字
like, I'm gonna get your name tattooed on me,
你敢嗎
call your bluff.
要是不敢  就還會有更可怕的事
If not, you've got to do some horrible shit.
通常你不會想做的
You don't generally want that,
所以我寧愿在屁股紋上他的名字
so I'd rather have this tattooed on my arse
也不愿接受其他的惡搞
than anything that he would inflict on me.
操你媽的
For fuck's sake.
好了
I think you're finished.
是嗎  謝謝  兄弟
I'm finished? Ah, thanks, mate.
我的天  兄弟  你現在牛逼了
Oh, my god. You are a legend, mate.
可你是不會得到獎勵的  知道嗎
But you are not gonna get a bird, you know that?
上次我玩這個游戲的時候
Last time I ever fucking play that game.
紋的是"上帝保佑阿伊納帕"
God bless Ayia Napa,
酒精和紋身店  真是相得益彰
alcohol, tattoo shops.
你就是個白癡
You're a dickhead, you know that?
今天  馬特要去完成覆蓋紋身的最后部分
Today, Matt is back for the final session on his chest cover-up.
但這次他不顧戴夫的建議
But this time, he's gone against Dave's advice.
他喝了點啤酒  太愚蠢了  不是嗎
He's had a few beers. That's a stupid thing to do, isn't it?
說了他也不聽
He never listens, does he?
希望他不要像剛喝完酒那樣
Let's hope he don't start talking away now,
絮絮叨叨說個不停
like he's had a few beers.
但對戴夫來說  這次工作似乎會很漫長
But it looks like it might be a long session for Dave.
你注意到這里了嗎
Can you notice this bit,
還是可以看到以前的紋身
that it's still showing through and that?
是的  我他媽還沒做完呢
Yeah, well, we haven't fucking finished yet.
我知道  只是說說
No, I know, I'm just saying.
給喝多了酒的人紋身
Tattooing someone who's had too much to drink
異常困難
is really hard work.
他們會變得話很多
They talk too much.
我非常喜歡野生動物
I really like my wildlife.
我可以就這樣坐著欣賞它們
I sit there and watch wildlife and that.
但這不是我紋這個圖案的原因
That ain't the reason why I got a tattoo done like,
原因是我愛老鷹  它們很迷人
because I love eagles, but they are really fascinating animals.
喝酒的人總是坐不住
They don't keep still,
頭老是動來動去
they're moving their head all over the place,
而且牽一發就動全身
which moves the rest of their body.
老鷹的體型超贊  而且神秘莫測
The way their body shape is, their like, stealth,
飛翔異常迅捷  能夠隨遇而安
how fast they fly and that, the way they adapt,
它們的顏色那么豐滿
their colours are lush.
酒醉的人容易煩躁  吵鬧不止
They fidget a lot and they're usually pretty boisterous.
而且它們竟然能在空中捕獲鳥兒
The fact that they can actually catch a bird in mid-air and that,
我的意思是  它們就是空中霸王
I mean, they fly like bastards.
但老實說  我還是很喜歡野生動物
I like a lot of my wildlife, though, to be honest.
最好不要給那些
It's just best not to tattoo people
喝醉酒的人紋身
who've had too much to drink at all, really.
馬特很不安定
With Matt so distracted,
戴夫發現很難完成紋身
Dave's finding it difficult to get the tattoo finished.
馬特一直抽煙  偶爾還要喝茶
Matt and his fags, tea breaks
該死的煙和酒
and bloody fags and drink,
弄得他根本沒法乖乖坐著
and you'd never get through a complete day
讓你好好的工作  是吧
with him in a chair, would you?
我剛剛看到他走出去
Well, I've just seen him going out there,
我想著不可能
I thought no, that can't be right.
我肯定是看錯了
My eyes are deceiving me.
是的  馬修就是一個傻逼
Yeah, Matthew is a C-U-N-T.
他就在外面  沒穿上衣
He's out there now with no clothes on.
外面很冷  他抽著煙  瑟瑟發抖
Freezing cold, shivering for a fag.
他就是一個煩人的噩夢
He's a bloody nightmare.
過去的這幾周里
But Matt's been having other problems of his own
馬特遇到了其他麻煩
over the past few weeks.
你在這里干什么工作
What is it you do down here?
-鏟車司機是嗎  -是的
- Are you a forklift driver? - Yeah, forklift driver.
我還沒真正丟了工作
I haven't actually lost my job yet,
但我知道這已經是板上釘釘了
I'm just pretty certain that it's gonna go.
為什么
Yeah, why's that?
很大程度上是因為我
A lot of it is me,
總是過于亢奮  話又很多
because I'm so hyper and so bubbly all the time.
一行有一行的規矩
But when it's just one rule for one and one rule for another,
不小心就玩過了
it just goes a bit far then, doesn't it?
我一氣之下就爆發了  該死的
I just blew up and lost my rag. Damn it.
他不僅工作失意
Not only is there trouble at work,
還和妻子離了婚
but he's broken up with his partner.
你現在住哪兒
Where are you living now?
搬回家和我爸媽住了
Back with my mam and dad now.
兩個孩子  一個破碎的家
I'm absolutely gutted that
對我的打擊太大了
I've got two kids from a broken home now.
我曾經深愛著我的太太
I mean, my missus, I love her to death
可我現在對她只有兄妹情誼  這你懂吧
but now I love her as a brother or sister, you know what I mean?
想到我孩子的處境  我就更難過了
Absolutely heartbroken with the situation with my kids, though.
傷心也于事無補
Heartbroken we couldn't make it work,
我腦海中的另一個聲音說
but then there's another side of me saying,
既然于事無補  不如好好活下去
oh, well, if you can't make it work, get on with your life.
好了  伙計
That's it, mate.
好看嗎
Job's a good 'un?
你照鏡子看看
Have a look in the mirror.
經過十多個小時的紋身
After more than ten hours of tattooing in Dave Fleet's chair,
戴夫·弗利特覆蓋了馬特的舊紋身
Matt's cover-up is finally complete.
他身上看不到一絲
And all evidence of his
阿伊納帕夢幻游艇派對紋身的痕跡
Ayia Napa fantasy boat party tattoo has gone.
太滿意了  非常高興  伙計
Well happy with that. Very happy with that, mate.
色彩飛揚紋身店
還好嗎  伙計
You all right, mate?
外面天氣不太好啊
Minging out there, isn't it?
是啊
Yeah, right.
今天  24歲的奧斯丁終于要把
Today, 24-year-old Austin is finally getting
紋在脖子上的前任的名字覆蓋過去了
the tattoo of his ex-girlfriend's name on his neck covered up.
不猶豫了吧
No time like the present, hey?
是的
Yep.
這可不像我之前紋過的
It's not...one of the easiest...
那么簡單
tattoos I've ever done.
要不是他頭上已經有個紋身
Had he not have had tattoos on his head already,
我可能都不會幫他紋
I wouldn't have tattooed his head.
這舉動有點瘋狂
It's a big statement to make.
他腦袋后面全是紋身
He's got them on the back of his head,
他還經常剃頭  把紋身露出來
he constantly bics his head, so it's always on show.
可以說
No,
他才不是那種怕把紋身露出來的人
he's not one of these guys that's afraid to get them out, as it were.
-你準備好了嗎  伙計  -準備好了
- All right, you ready, bud? - Yep.
我知道滿臉紋身的我很嚇人
I do think I look intimidating with tattoos all over my face
一看就不像好人  可我本性并非如此
and I definitely do look like a thug, but I'm not.
我曾經是個壞小子  但現在不是了
I used to be, but I'm not.
我小時候有多動癥
I had ADHD when I was younger,
嚴重影響了我的行為舉止
which had, obviously, a big influence on my behaviour.
這個位置太不順手了
It's an awkward fucking position.
以前我在外總是闖禍
I used to go out causing trouble all the time,
到處打架  就是個惹事精
fighting all the time, just a right little menace.
見什么搶什么
Robbing everything,
不尊重任何人  任何事
just didn't have no respect for anyone or anything.
我媽媽拿我一點辦法都沒有
My mum couldn't cope with me,
于是把我丟給了養父母
so she chucked me into foster parents
要不就是送到養護中心
and care homes and I went through,
這都是家常便飯了
obviously, all that sort of process.
我被準許回家以后  又惹了更大的麻煩
I was allowed to come back home and got into more trouble
最后進了監獄
and then ended up going to prison.
再見  黛西
Bye, bye, Daisy.
黛西  再見
Daisy, goodbye.
說實話  我曾試圖開槍打死我媽
Basically, I tried to shoot my mum.
為此我感到羞愧  不過我倆現在和好了
It's something I'm not proud of. Obviously, we get on now,
我那時太年輕  太愚蠢
but yeah, I was young, stupid,
嗑藥成癮  什么都不在乎
drugged up and just didn't care about anything.
我前后三次入獄
Three times I've been inside, I think.
我再也不想回去了
But yeah, I won't be going back.
說實話  入獄讓我成長了很多
Going to prison made me grow up loads, to be honest.
有了孩子之后
And then having children
才懂得人不能只顧自己
and knowing that I had to fend for somebody else,
還要照顧他人
it wasn't just for myself.
顯然  我要是坐牢去了
Obviously, I couldn't look after my kids
就沒法照顧孩子們了
if I was inside prison,
凡事都要以孩子為重
so, obviously, they have to come first now.
永遠都要把孩子放在首位
Children have always got to come first.
奧斯丁在椅子上坐了兩個小時了
Austin has now been sitting for two hours.
太他媽疼了
So fucking sore now, I'll tell ya.
我能想象的到  伙計
Yeah, I can imagine, mate.
羅德爭取盡快完成紋身
But Rod is struggling to get the tattoo finished.
血止不住地往外流
It won't stop fucking bleeding.
你瞧  血一直往外冒
You can see the blood pushing it out there.
奧斯丁出血太多
Austin is bleeding so much
羅德不得不在同一個圖案上紋兩遍
that Rod is having to tattoo the same areas twice.
出血過多是不是就得重新紋一遍
Will you go over it again if it pushes it out badly, or not?
是啊  必須得這樣
Yeah, I'd have to.
血把好多墨都帶出來了  弄得到處都是
It'd just push too much of the ink out, it'd be all blotchy.
三個小時過后
After three hours of tattooing, Rod has no choice
羅德只能提前結束這次紋身
but to stop the session earlier than he'd like.
紋身不能超過皮膚的承受能力  知道嗎
No, I can't over-work the skin, mate, do you know what I mean?
我改天再約你吧
I'm gonna call that a day.
行  沒事  伙計
Yeah, that's fine, mate.
改天還得再過來潤色一下
You'll have to come back for a touch-up,
我估計你現在一定很疼
because I can imagine you're in a bit of pain now.
相當疼
It's fucking sore.
黛西的名字沒了
Daisy, gone.
確實  正合我意
Yeah, that's bang on.
我再也不想把任何女孩的名字紋在身上了
I definitely don't want any more girls' names tattooed on me.
這倆紋身可讓我長了教訓
I think I've learnt from these two.
我肯定再也不會這么干了
I shan't be doing that again, definitely not.
什么名字也不紋了
No more names.
在威爾士的坦希勒斯
In Llanhilleth, Wales, Matt is
失業外加離異的馬特
now living with his parents, having lost his job
現在和父母住在一起
and split up from his partner.
她不讓我見孩子
She's stopped me from seeing the baby,
首先  我要解決住房問題
like, so get on top of things first, get my flat sorted
然后再上法庭爭取撫養權
and then I'll go into court then.
我享有和她平等的權利
I got just as much rights as her.
現在我準備
Getting ready now to go
在背后紋上我女兒的畫像了
and have a portrait of my daughter being done on my back,
這樣無論結果如何  我女兒都會知道
so no matter what the outcome is, my daughter will always know
我從未忘記她  她就是我的全部
I've never forgotten about her and she means the world to me.
魔咒紋身店
讓我看看
So, let me have a look.
天啊
Oh, my God.
你怎么能醉成這樣
How could you be so drunk
連身上紋的什么都不知道
as you didn't know what you was having?
我知道是句臟話  我這人就這樣
Oh, I knew what I was having done, it's just me, isn't it?
不錯  這個圖案適合你
Right, stand as you are, nice and still.
太完美了
Absolutely perfect.
我干了三十四年
In 34 years,
還沒見過往自己身上刺臟話的
I've never seen anyone with swearing on them.
你在那邊  一出門
It's just like, when you're out there,
總有人向你推薦各式各樣的酒吧
they promote different clubs and all that.
還有紋身店
But they promoted the tattoo places as well.
這么說來
So, you're saying that that tattooist
給你紋臟話的師傅是在推銷生意咯
putting a four-letter word on you is promoting him?
那你說我要是讓你在那邊紋個"笨蛋"
So do you think if I put, "Twat", on the other side,
是不是還給我創收呢
it might fucking help me or what?
你倒提醒了我  不能和你們出去喝酒
Remind me never to go out drinking with you guys.
指不定和誰酒后亂性
I don't know what I'd go home with.
連馬特都開始覺得該向前看了
But even Matt is starting to think it's time to move on.
我從阿伊納帕回來后
Since I've come home from Ayia Napa, I think it's just, like,
覺得玩夠了
because I've done my fair share of partying,
我想安定下來了
you know what I mean, I want to settle down and that.
和家人一起度假什么的
Like, have family holidays and shit like that,
我只想好好休息一下
I just want to chill back a bit.
是的  我成熟點了
Yes, I am growing up a bit.
我要有自己的公寓  重新開始工作
I'm gonna get my own flat and all that, get back into work,
這樣我才能獲得孩子的共同撫養權
so I can go in for joint custody of my kids.
才能再見到我的孩子們
So I can actually get to see my kids and that again.
馬特還是原來的他  只是變得更懂事了
Well, not a new Matt, just a bit more sensible one, like.
我還是喜歡玩  只是更有節制了
I'll still have fun, but it's just have it in moderation,
比如每周只玩六天而不是天天玩
like six days a week instead of seven.
歇會兒
Sit back.
謝天謝地  開始有點疼了
Thank God for that, it was starting to hurt a bit then.
才開始疼  你剛疼得像青蛙似的上躥下跳
Starting to hurt? You were jumping about like a box of frogs.
我從未認真對待過生活
Yeah, I'll never, ever take life too serious.
你告訴我  生活的意義是什么
You tell me, what is the point of life?
活著就是生活  死了  生活就沒了
We're here till we die. When we die, there is no more life,
所以趁還活著不妨好好享樂  對不對
so you might as well have fun whilst you're here, innit?
懂了嗎
Do you know what I mean?
一旦你停止作樂
Once you stop having fun,
倒不如死去  說簡單點就是這個意思
that's when you might as well be dead, simple as.
非常好  說真的  我很喜歡
Very good, fair play, I like that.